Digital Marketing Executive & SEO Analyst

Professional Summary

A role having 2+ years of experience in the IT Industry. Well - Versed with SEO approaches of Off-Page & On-page Optimization techniques & SEO content creation. Being qualified in MSCIT, strength to coordinate with the Designer/Developer to make technical adjustments to web pages to ensure they are constructed in a way that does not prevent search engines from indexing.

Experience

SEO Analyst October 2020 - Current

INDA SEO PVT LTD, Ahmedabad, Gujarat

- Analyzed & audited reports of 10+ client's websites to address performance issues by 80%.
- Utilize keyword research tools to track progress & performance.
- Improved 30% of keyword ranking by enhancing Blogs for the focused key phrase & Webpages & content of the website.
- Developed on-site body content, meta descriptions & title tags, internal linking in support of SEO Strategies.
- Understanding of HTML, CSS & Technical SEO code structure including XML sitemap submissions, robots.txt files, Schema Markup Generator.
- Analyzing the site from the SEO point of view & Implementing 301 and 404 Redirect, Correcting Broken Links, Canonical Redirect.
- Working on 30+ clients in a month especially for on-site Activities with expected results.
- Off-Page activities for 10+ clients by building 30+ backlinks a day.

Digital Marketing Executive

June 2019 - September 2020

metR Technology, Ahmedabad, Gujarat

- Worked on multiple categories based on Service or Product Business.
- Reviewed & optimized 12 client sites to improve keyword targeting URL strategies, website architecture & content.
- Built, implemented by utilizing effective SEO & emphasized the importance of link building.
- Created solution-based execution plans to achieve by **Google Analytics** & internal reporting data.
- Communicated with 5-10 calls per day to address customer inquiries & concerns.
- Presented detailed monthly reporting & analysis on client website demographics & statistics using Google Analytics.
- Supported clients to develop website portals & social media pages to promote business brand awareness through the creation & management of social media platforms & channels.
- Demonstrated exceptional knowledge & experience working in Billing Software products.
- Resolving Client 100% problems, improved operations & provided exceptional client support.
- Focused traffic growth strategies, including SEO, affiliate link Building activities with content distribution.
- Generated over more than 200 clicks for booming organic search.
- Accomplished in 5+ industry-leading successes & profitability goals by developing & implementing all off-page & on-page activities & blogs to the website through 3-layer link-building activities for security.
- Turned 2 **clients** from negative to positive by serving customers to meet their expectations.

Internship

January 2019 - May 2019

metR Technology, Ahmedabad, Gujarat

Tools Google Analytics

- Lighthouse
- Semrush
- Website SEO checker
- Google Webmaster
- Bing Webmaster
- Yandex Webmaster

Domains

- WordPress •
- GoDaddy
- Shopify
- Square
- Web4realty
- CmS

Social Media

- Hoot suite
- Facebook
- Instagram •
- LinkedIn
- Twitter

Education

Master's in Computer Application & Information Technology

MSC (CA & IT) | Aggregate: 3.53 GPA BSC (CA & IT) | Aggregate: 2.40 GPA **KS School of Business Management**

ASIA ENGLISH SCHOOL - Ahmedabad, Gujarat

2014-2017 2000-2014

2017-2019

Certifications

Webinar On How to run PROFITABLE FACEBOOK ADS

IELTS: Overall Band 6 & Each 6

ASDM (Ahmedabad School of Digital Marketing) - Advance Digital

June 2021

February 2020

September 2018